Guide to the Frank L. Berry, Jr. family papers, 1876-2004 MS 564
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Frank L. Berry, Jr. family papers
1876-2004
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Berry, Frank Lee (Jr.)
MS 564
3.75 Linear Feet (8 boxes)
10.4 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0564aip_001 PDF of diary and master files
The collection documents the history of Frank Lee Berry, Jr. and his family. Included are photographs, correspondence, genealogical information, and family records.
Biographical Note
Frank Lee Berry, Jr., son of Frank Lee Berry and Louie Todd Berry, was born in Houston's South End on June 15, 1921. He graduated from San Jacinto High School in 1939 and the University of Houston in 1943. His military service included serving in the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers in Germany during 1945-46. He was an interior designer for more than 50 years, serving both AID and ASID at local, state, and national levels and was elected a fellow in the American Institute of Interior Designers in 1972. Berry died April 15, 2004 in Houston and is buried at Brookside Memorial Park.
Berry was a third generation Houstonian and his parents, Frank Lee Berry and Louie Todd Berry, were prominent early Houstonians. Berry's grandfather, James Berry, moved to Texas from Kentucky in 1836 to fight in the Battle of San Jacinto as a First Lieutenant in the Republic of Texas' army. In 1840 James Berry moved to northern Harris County near Greens Bayou. He served as Justice of the Peace (1840-53) and Treasurer of Harris County from 1854 to 1857, Civilian Director for Harris County during the Civil War (1861-65), and as a county school commissioner until his death in 1876. Both Berry Road and Berry Elementary School were named in his honor. Berry Cemetery, on the site of the original Berry family home, has been incorporated into the current Brookside Memorial Park.
Scope and Contents
The collection documents the history of Frank Lee Berry, Jr. and his family. Included are photographs, correspondence, genealogical information, and family records.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was donated by the Heritage Society at Sam Houston Park [Houston, TX] via the estate of Frank Lee Berry, Jr., Oct. 12, 2010.
Index Terms
Subjects
Social life and customs
Document Types
letters (correspondence); genealogies (histories); financial records; scrapbooks; photographs
Places
Texas -- Houston
Subjects (Persons)
Berry, Frank Lee (Jr.)
- Series I: Photographs, 216925
  - Frank Lee Berry, 216926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Frank Lee Berry & others, 216927 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Frank Berry house, Austin St. @ Anita, Houston, TX, 1904; 216928 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Louie Todd Berry (Mrs. Frank L.), 216929 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Louise Todd & others, 1890s; 216930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Frank Lee Berry, Jr., 216931 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Frank L. Berry, Jr. & others, 216932 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Louie Lee Berry, 216933 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - F.L. Berry children photo album, 216934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - James Berry, 216962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - James Berry house, Paxton, TX, 216963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Alice Berry, 216964 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Myrtle Berry, 216965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Roston Berry, 216966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Berry family, 216967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Hallie Swift Todd, 216968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Hallie S. Todd & others, 216969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Louis Byrd Todd, 216973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Mrs. L.B. Todd, 216975 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Mary Ann Durr Todd, 216976 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Todd family, 216977 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Durr family, 216983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Sallie Durr Archer, 216982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Alice Archer (Mrs. Chris Berg), 216984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Elizabeth Archer (Mrs. Cannon), 216985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Thomas Whitworth Archer, 216986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Alice, Elizabeth, Whit Archer, 1898; 216987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Elizabeth & Philmer Archer, 1901; 216988 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Archer-Cannon family, 216990 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Mary A. Durkee & grandchildren, ca. 1912; 216998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Durkee house, Elizabeth St., Houston, TX, 217007 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - James Madison Cotton, 217011 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - James M. Cotton & others, 217016 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - James M. Cotton house, Rosalie & LaBranch, Houston, TX, 217022 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - James M. Cotton house, 1018 Travis & Lamar, Houston, TX, 217023 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Lizzie Cotton (Mrs. J.M.), 217024 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Grandfather Cotton, 217025 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Addie Cotton Munson, 217026 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Houston Cotton, 217027 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Steven Olin Cotton, 217028 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Houston Cotton Munson, 217029 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Cotton family cemetery plot, Glenwood Cemetery, Houston, TX, 217120 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Nella Cochran, 217122 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Owen L. Cochran, 217125 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Owen L. Cochran Jr., 1888; 217128 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Cochran family, 217131 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Lizzie Schluter Torrans, 217137 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bessie Torrans, 217138 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Tom Lee Torrans, 217139 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Schluter family, 217140 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Adams-Bell-Holt families, 217141 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Heffner family, 217142 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Lemmon family, 217143 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - O'Pry family, 217144 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Rankin family, 217149 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Crowley family, 217151 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Friends, 217152 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
  - Berry house servants, 217157 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Unknown, 217161 (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
  - Houston school classes, 217714 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Charlotte Baldwin Allen School, 217715 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Kidd Key Finishing School for Girls, Sherman, TX, 217716 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Fannin Elementary faculty, 1966; 217717 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Denton Cooley School faculty, 1966; 217718 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Houston Land & Trust Co., Main @ Fannin, Houston, TX, 217721 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Berry-Stone Lumber Co. office, 1st National Bank Building, Main @ Franklin, ca. 1917; 217723 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Bering Hardware Store, 217724 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Central Depot, Washington St., Houston, TX, 217725 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Houses built by Uncle Jim Berry on Caroline St., Houston, TX, 217726 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - House-Austin, TX, 217727 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Floods, 217728 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Series II: Correspondence, 217729
  - Frank L. Berry, 1900s-1930s; 217730 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Louie Todd Berry, 1900s-1979, n.d.; 217731 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Death of Louie Todd Berry (Mrs. Frank L.), 1979-1980; 217740 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Louie Lee Berry, 217737 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Frank L. Berry Jr., 1920s-1990s; 217743 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Cotton family, 1903, 1930s, 1993, 2004; 218071 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Todd family, 1876, 1910s, n.d.; 218073 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Berry family, 1893, 1910s, 1920s-30s, n.d.; 218074 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - General, 1910s-1970s; 218075 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Series III: Family records, 218274
  - Berry family genealogy, 218277 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Cemetery records, 218629 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Obituaries, 218631 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Wills, 218729 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Memorial book, Louie Todd Berry, 218739 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Memorial book, Hallie Swift Todd, 218740 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Newsclips, 219608 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Notes & writing, 219609 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Schooling, 219610 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Olympics, 1936; 219612 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Sheet music, 219617 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Berry School, 219620 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - James Berry farm, 219621 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Legal, 219622 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Receipts, 219623 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Stock certificates, 219626 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Trip to England-Hallie S. Todd, Frank Berry, Alice A. Bell, 1920; 219633 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Mrs. Frank L. Berry, 219636 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Frank L. Berry Jr., 219678
    - General, 219679 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Biographical, 219680 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Recollections, 219681 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Activities, 219682 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Sketches, 219683 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Schooling, 219684 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Interior design notebook, 219685 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Interior design model, 219687 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - World War II items removed from Weimar Museum, 1945; 219686 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Rice University Endowed Fund, 2000; 219688 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Louie Lee Berry diary of student life at Rice Institute, 1922-1925 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Series IV: Oversize, 219689
  - Memorabilia, 219691; 3.75 Linear Feet (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Materials are open for research.
  - Abstracts, Houston, TX, 219693 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Frank L. Berry Jr. San Jacinto High School scrapbook, 1936-39; 219700 (Box 8, Item 4)
  - James M. Cotton house, Rosalie & LaBranch, Houston, TX, interior views, 219703 (Box 8, Folder 5)